const quizData = [
  {
    question: "What your boyfriend?",
    a: "John",
    b: "Bob",
    c: "Thinh HandSome Boy",
    d: "Doe",
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "How old is he?",
    a: "12",
    b: "13",
    c: "20",
    d: "19",
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "Are you the type of person?",
    a: "Beautiful girl",
    b: "Messy",
    c: "Lazy",
    d: "All of them",
    correctAnswer: "d",
  },
  {
    question: "Do you take a bath?",
    a: "Not too much",
    b: "Yes, I do",
    c: "Never",
    d: "Sometime",
    correctAnswer: "d",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the brand of your laptop?",
    a: "Lenovo",
    b: "Hp",
    c: "Dell",
    d: "MacBook",
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "What is color of the leaves?",
    a: "Green",
    b: "Yellow",
    c: "Blue",
    d: "Red",
    correctAnswer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "What is most color of body's tree?",
    a: "Green",
    b: "Yellow",
    c: "Blue",
    d: "Brown",
    correctAnswer: "d",
  },
  {
    question: "What is color of the water?",
    a: "Green",
    b: "None",
    c: "white",
    d: "Red",
    correctAnswer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "What is color of cherry?",
    a: "Green",
    b: "Yellow",
    c: "Blue",
    d: "Red",
    correctAnswer: "d",
  },
  {
    question: "What is color of the orange fruit?",
    a: "Green",
    b: "Yellow",
    c: "orange",
    d: "Red",
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the famous brand of the phone?",
    a: "Iphone",
    b: "SamSung",
    c: "Oppo",
    d: "Nokia",
    correctAnswer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "What type of your laptop?",
    a: "Dell",
    b: "Hp",
    c: "Lenovo",
    d: "Macbook",
    correctAnswer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "What keeps you cool in the summer in the room?",
    a: "Air conditioning",
    b: "dryer",
    c: "fridge",
    d: "fan",
    correctAnswer: "a",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What helps you to charge your phone when you don't have an outlet?",
    a: "small music",
    b: "speaker",
    c: "airpods",
    d: "close the door",
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the famous brand of the phone?",
    a: "USB drive",
    b: "calculator",
    c: "power outlet",
    d: "backup charger",
    correctAnswer: "d",
  },
];

const quiz = document.getElementById("quiz");
const answerEls = document.querySelectorAll(".answer");
const questionEl = document.getElementById("question");
const a_text = document.getElementById("a_text");
const b_text = document.getElementById("b_text");
const c_text = document.getElementById("c_text");
const d_text = document.getElementById("d_text");
const buttonSubmit = document.getElementById("buttonSubmit");

let currentQuiz = 0;
let score = 0;

loadQuiz();
function loadQuiz() {
  deselectAnswer();

  const currentQuizData = quizData[currentQuiz];

  questionEl.innerText = currentQuizData.question;
  a_text.innerText = currentQuizData.a;
  b_text.innerText = currentQuizData.b;
  c_text.innerText = currentQuizData.c;
  d_text.innerText = currentQuizData.d;
}

function getSelected() {
  let answer = undefined;

  answerEls.forEach((answerEl) => {
    if (answerEl.checked) {
      answer = answerEl.id;
    }
  });
  return answer;
}

function deselectAnswer() {
  answerEls.forEach((answerEl) => {
    answerEl.checked = false;
  });
}
buttonSubmit.addEventListener("click", () => {
  const answer = getSelected();
  if (answer) {
    if (answer === quizData[currentQuiz].correctAnswer) {
      score++;
    }
    currentQuiz++;

    if (currentQuiz < quizData.length) {
      loadQuiz();
    } else {
      quiz.innerHTML = `
                <h2>You answered correctly at ${score}/${quizData.length} questions. Miss TÃº!</h2>
                
                <button onclick="location.reload()">Reload</button>
            `;
    }
  }
});
